So, we want to jack the vehicle up.
We don't want to jack it up to such an angle that it's going to create a hazard or danger by tilting or applying too much force on the other side.
So, I've got it up with the tire probably around a foot off the ground and that's more than adequate to give us plenty of room to work and keep a good safety margin.
So, this time, once I've got it jacked up, I'm going to put it on a jack stand or another device to safely carry the load.
I place that jack stand underneath the frame right at the very front where the unibody frame comes up and the front suspension meet.
It's a good place to stabilize and carry the load.
Now, turning counter-clockwise very slowly, it kinda--when you break this free, it's going to want to turn fast.
So, you gotta kinda be careful and regulate it.
What I want to do is just slowly lower the vehicle on to that jack so the jacks could--or the jack stand so the jack stand's carrying the load.
So it'll be able to slowly settle down and let it come to a stop and I like to leave the jack in there as another safety feature.
It's not carrying the load right now, it's just at--it's just below where the frame is.
I let the jack stand carry the load but the jack is left in place in case of a failure.
Please watch our next segment on removing the front tire.